# LAUREN NOELTNER

Atlanta, Georgia 30306

Phone: (404) 376-7192 | Email: laurennoeltner@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/lauren-noeltner-102b731a0 | GitHub: https://www.github.com/LNoeltner1/ | Portfolio: https://lauren-noeltner.herokuapp.com/

#### SUMMARY

Full-Stack Junior Web Developer, bringing skills from previous experience in design, problem solving, and efficient communication into web development. Authored the official employee manual for a chain of three stores, won an Above and Beyond award, and won employee of the month on several occasions. Graduate of Georgia Tech's Full Stack Flex Web Development certification program with an A average. Lifelong learner with a passion for creating new tools that work well and look good. Known for a willingness to go beyond expectations and doing whatever it takes to successfully complete any task.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Page Design: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Foundation

Primary Language: JavaScript

Technologies/frameworks: React, Node.js, Express, jQuery, Handlebars, and more

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, Sequelize, NoSQL

Development Tools: Version control/deployment with GitHub and Heroku, Git, Visual Studio

Code, MongoDB Atlas, Robo3T, MySQL Workbench, Postman, Chrome DevTools

## **PROJECTS**

- Cryptic Encounters
  - Responsibilities: Front and Back End, dialogue mapping/logic, Design, Concept
  - Tech used: JavaScript, Handlebars, Node.js, Express, MySQL, Foundation
  - Link to Github: <a href="https://github.com/LNoeltner1/cryptic-encounters">https://github.com/LNoeltner1/cryptic-encounters</a>
  - Link to Deployment: <a href="https://cryptic-encounter.herokuapp.com/">https://cryptic-encounter.herokuapp.com/</a>
- GiddyltUp
  - Responsibilities: Front and Back End, CRUD management, Design, Concept
  - Tech used: JavaScript, MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js, Bootstrap, Animate.css
  - Link to Github: https://github.com/LNoeltner1/GiddyItUp
  - Link to Deployment: https://giddyitup-eq.herokuapp.com/
- The Everything Converter
  - Responsibilities: All (solo project)
  - Tech Used: JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express, currency exchange API
  - Link to GitHub: https://github.com/LNoeltner1/the\_everything\_calculator
  - Link to Deployment: <a href="https://everything-converter.herokuapp.com/">https://everything-converter.herokuapp.com/</a>

## **EXPERIENCE**

Team Lead

April 2019-August 2020 Atlanta, Georgia

Regal Entertainment Group

Lead a team of up to 15 floor staff members to provide high quality customer service

 Assisted the General Manager with creating a checklist for all floor staff responsibilities to increase productivity and accountability

Cast Member February 2017-April 2019

Regal Entertainment Group

Atlanta, Georgia

- Collaborated with a team to provide high quality customer service
- Spent extra time cleaning and organizing to ensure a safe and healthy workspace for all
- Established and maintained positive relationships with customers by answering their questions and fixing any issues brought up

# **Assistant Manager**

June 2016-August 2016

Victorious Vapors, LLC

Athens, Georgia

- Created and managed all special discounts and sales to attract more customers and profit
- Maintained top sales numbers (>\$55,000 over 8 months)
- Wrote employee manual to make the onboarding process quicker and more efficient

Sales Associate August 2015-June 2016

Victorious Vapors, LLC

Athens, Georgia

• Developed a strong rapport with clients, creating a wide base of recurring, loyal customers

Dog-Sitter/Walker May 2012-Present

Freelance pet-care business

Atlanta, Georgia

Established a successful side business of pet-care with 100% client return rate

Kennel Technician

June 2008-August 2013

Briarcliff Animal Clinic

College Park, Georgia

- Assisted doctors with treatments, diagnoses, and surgeries to ensure pet health
- Maintained medical records to keep an accurate account of an animal's condition

# Key Accomplishments:

- Wrote employee manual for a chain of 3 stores to codify policy and simplify onboarding
- Always communicate effectively to ensure maximum positive results
- Won several local and national painting awards

#### **EDUCATION**

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development, Georgia Institute of Technology, November 2020

 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars and React

## Relevant courses, University of Georgia

Color and Composition, 3D Design, Research Statistics, Psychology courses, Physics